我们的应用需要适配所有
So, we need to build an app that adapts well to
不同的设备  但是设备的类型太多了
all different devices. But there's so many types of devices. So,
我们如何下手呢  我们可以先按照尺寸
where do we begin? Well, we can start by grouping them
大小来区分他们  我们把手机
into buckets based on physical size. We can have a bucket for
和7寸、10寸的平板
phones and a bucket for seven inch tablets. And a bucket
分成三类  你也可以根据屏幕宽度
for ten inch tablets as well. You can go even more granular
来区分他们  不过这都是一些较为常见的
based on screen width. But these are the most common buckets
区分方法  事实上只根据大小来区分他们是远远不够的
that you'll need. Now, classifying based on size alone is not enough.
即便他们的大小相同  他们的屏幕密度(DPI)
Even among devices of the same size, there's still
也不尽相同  屏幕密度的计算方法是
a wide range of screen densities. Screen density is calculated
设备的每英寸有多少的像素点
from the number of dots per inch on the device
简称DPI  最小的是Low DPI
or DPI. Scale starts off with low density devices, also
它每英寸仅有120个像素点
known as LDPI devices. It has about 120 dots
再高一点的是 MDPI、HDPI 再高的就是
per inch, then it increases to medium density, high density
XDPI、XXDPI、XXXDPI 等等  它越高就代表这
all the way to extra, extra, extra high density devices
单位英寸可以显示的像素点越多
were the number of dots per inch is much higher.
那么我们该如何让我们的应用
So, how do we build an app that accounts for
适配这么多不同的屏幕密度呢  我们指定布局的尺寸时
all these different screen densities? Well, when we specify layout dimensions,
我们应该知道我们不能用像素来做大小标识了
we quickly realize that we can't use pixels. For example,
比如一个48像素大小的按钮  在MDPI的设备上看起来还可以
a 48 pixel button that looks fine on an MDPI device
但是在高清的设备上
will look much smaller on a higher density device where
估计就会显得48像素
the pixels are more compacted and the physical size of 48
太低了  用户肯定希望这个按钮很容易
pixels is much smaller. The user wants a button to be
点击  而且按钮不应该随着屏幕的大小而改变
easily tappable, and so it shouldn't change based on screen density.
所以我们需要一个统一的计量单位来表示物理大小
So we need a consistent unit of measure to define physical
在Android里  我们称之为与密度无关的像素  或者叫 dips
size, and in Android we call that density-independent pixels or dips
或者称之为dp  所以一个40dp 的按钮
or dp for short. That way, a 48 dp button will
在所有不同大小设备里看起来就是一样的了
be the same physical size across all these different screen densities.